<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!-- Works for Firefox, Safari and Chrome -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="application/xml" href="xsl/html5.xsl" ?>
<!-- Needed for Internet Explorer -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/html5.xsl" ?>

<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "./page.dtd">

<page>

&header;

<section name="Planning Daisy for V5 Alteration" id="main">
<text>
<value>Barry put his skills to work and planned out a couple of simple layouts on 3D Max (a CAD/3D Graphics application). Louise's dad cut out scale models of the van and caravan furniture. This allowed us to move the furniture around to see what was feasible. Both of these planning methods allowed us to rule out a number of layouts.</value>
<flickr photoid="6869275647" group="layout"/>
<flickr photoid="6869275739" group="layout"/>
<flickr photoid="6869275837" group="layout"/>
<flickr photoid="6869275909" group="layout"/>
<flickr photoid="6871800115" group="layout"/>
<flickr photoid="6871800017" group="layout"/>
</text>
<text>
<value>We moved the furniture around and came up with 2 possible layouts, 1 keeping the back door usable and another blocking off the doors with the bathroom/wardrobe. Eventually we opted for closing off the backdoors for a few reasons; first it saved "dressing up" the inside of the doors; second it allowed us a "work" area for the gas bottles, toilet, tools and other stuff we didn't want inside the living area. This we thought was a much better option than being able to use the back doors as a loading bay (it's a camper, not a van).</value>
<flickr photoid="6869555761" group="plan"/>
</text>
<text>
<value>Barry then continued with the 3D max version by modeling the virtual van accurately in terms of height and shape and building the layouts we'd chosen. We scanned and downloaded swatches of fabrics and wallboards to help decide what would look best before we purchased the materials.</value>
<flickr photoid="6869286081" group="interiordesign"/>
<flickr photoid="6869288555" group="interiordesign"/>
<video width="320" height="240" name="beddesignframe" description="Rendering of how the bed frame could work"/>
<video width="320" height="240" name="beddesignwithcushions" description="Rendering of how the cushions could fit"/>
</text>
<text>
<value>Louise's sister had some left over insulation from her garage conversion, so we kindly took it off of her hands. The rest of the insulation came from the caravan roof which conveniently was not glued in place. We used sheets of acoustic foam insulation purchased from a Leroy Merlin in Malaga for the roof and various door insulation.</value>
</text>
<text>
<value>We fitted the skylights at the same time as the ceiling boards, but for insurance reasons, waited until we were with a self-build motorhome insurance policy before starting the windows.</value>
</text>
<text>
<value>Once we had put up all of the wall boards and ceiling board it was time to partition the van into separate areas. We planned the bed/seats out in our heads and designed it in 3D Max. Louise's Dad put theory into practice and came up with a working bed and chair. We wanted a bed that would fold out relatively easily, be 6'4" long and wide enough for two adults. When not a bed, it can be converted to a bench or a central table and two single chairs facing each other. Combined with the fixed size shower based extracted from the caravan, we had the measurements needed to define the modifications required for the kitchen unit and the wardrobe location. Originally we planned to have a half height wardrobe above the gas bottles at the back giving some floor space in front. This was shelved in favour of pulling the wardrobe behind the chair giving a full height version conveniently hiding the wheel arch (where a set of drawers were originally planned to fit). This would give us more room for essential storage!</value>
<flickr photoid="6869288837" group="bedv1"/>
<flickr photoid="6869288175" group="bedv1"/>
<flickr photoid="6869288083" group="bedv1"/>
<flickr photoid="6869288001" group="bedv1"/>
</text>
<text>
<value>When installing the seats we had to make sure the fresh water container would fit under one seat and that the gas water heater would fit under the other as we didn't want the fresh water tank outside the living area. Louise's dad cut down the caravan seat and made up additional supports for bench mode and bed mode. The cushions were also taken from the caravan. Louise's mum made cushion covers out of upholstery fabric purchased from eBay.</value>
</text>
<text>
<value>The kitchen unit from the caravan fitted perfectly length ways, but we had to cut down the width and make it flush as it was originally partly recessed. The bathroom shower base fitted perfectly between the back door and wheel arch, it even had an indentation where the diesel filling pipe was situated. It was as if it was made for it. We didn't want to buy a brand new worktop because we felt it may get damaged during the build, so we obtained a scrap wardrobe from IKEA and cut one of the sides to size. The unit has been designed to allow the worktop to be removed and replaced after it has been installed.</value>
</text>
<text>
<value>We needed to use the van before deciding how to finish the bathroom door, so we installed the one used from the caravan, unfortunately this was a little too big and made it impossible to open when the bed was down. Over the winter we had the bathroom door trimmed and cut into two halves and hinged them together to make a bi-fold door. The door looked quite bland so we decided to put mirrored acrylic plastic on each side.</value>
<flickr photoid="6869289155" group="bifold"/>
<flickr photoid="6869289299" group="bifold"/>
<video width="320" height="240" name="slidingdoor" description="How the sliding door would look"/>
</text>

<text>
<value>There is a plastic shelf above the driver cab which currently houses the charging unit taken from the caravan, to the right of this unit we have installed white hardboard base and sides and the ceiling board curving to the front. This brightens up the overcab, storage area and will form a cupboard to store towels and blankets. This is ideal, because we have used the existing frame of the shelf for strength, but hidden it with nicer looking materials. Once finished, this gives a height measurement for the planned over-kitchen over-seat cupboards.</value>
<flickr photoid="6869555313" group="cupboards"/>
<flickr photoid="6869555639" group="cupboards"/>
<flickr photoid="6869555551" group="cupboards"/>
<flickr photoid="6869555433" group="cupboards"/>
</text>

<text>
<value>Here is the plan for the replacement bed, this was designed after 2 years usage of the previous (temporary) system. We specifically tackled the problematic and inconvenient features of the old style one.</value>
<flickr photoid="6870784953" group="bedv2"/>
<flickr photoid="6869556157" group="bedv2"/>
<flickr photoid="6869556457" group="bedv2"/>
<flickr photoid="6869556783" group="bedv2"/>
<flickr photoid="6869557041" group="bedv2"/>
<flickr photoid="7728041870" group="bedv2"/>
</text>
</section>

<section name="Water" id="water">
<text>
<value>We wanted a hot water supply as well as cold, so took advantage of the carver heater extracted from the caravan. We used the 3D Max plans to decide the best size and position for the fresh and waste water tanks (to be ordered from C.A.K. tanks) and the route and length of water pipes. C.A.K. were very helpful as they added necessary outlets to the tanks for us and included all the necesary water pipe fittings and pipes in the order. The water tank was fitted with an attachment so it could be used with a submersible pump. </value>
<flickr photoid="6872259095" group="waterroute"/>
<flickr photoid="6872258947" group="waterroute"/>
<flickr photoid="6872258773" group="waterroute"/>
<flickr photoid="6872258619" group="waterroute"/>
</text>
<text>
<value>
We originally wanted to use the supplementary side hatch on the van to access the water tank so it could be filled from outside.
</value>
<flickr photoid="6869287661" group="exteriorplan"/>
</text>
</section>

<section name="Electricity" id="electricity">
<text>
<value>We did not put anywhere near enough thought into what we wanted in the van before we started wallboarding, as a result we ended up finding novel ways of hiding wires behind furniture and facings rather than behind the wallboards and ceiling boards like we should have. The following wiring diagram has evolved over time and given hindsight, should have been the first thing we did! 
</value>
<flickr photoid="7425184558" group="electrics"/>
</text>
<text>
<value>
We planned to use the ZIG CF2000 unit recovered from the caravan to distribute power to appliances and charge the leisure battery when driving by connecting the ZIG to the leisure battery and van battery. The fridge would be wired directly to the van battery. The only wiring we planned for was the battery connections; fridge (12V and 240V); bathroom light; toilet flush; a 12v socket at the kitchen; and a single light in the centre of the van. We calculated how much wiring was required for the submersible pump and microswitch cabling would be routed along side the cold water pipes where possible through the furniture and wallboards during construction. 
</value>
</text>
</section>

<section name="Gas" id="gas">
<text>
<value>
We planned to use all the appliances recycled from the donor caravan we the exception of the heater and after deciding on the layout, the appliance positions were added to the 3D Max layout so the gas pipes could be routed and measured, and manifold positioned in optimal places. 
</value>
<flickr photoid="6872258467" group=""/>
</text>

<text>
<value>
The gas box was designed to hold two 15kg size Calor Butane gas bottles which are 580mm tall with a diameter of 318mm, this would allow us to accomodate two 15kg or two 7kg (495mm height, 256mm diameter) or one of each. We obtained some steel, checkerplate flooring, dropout vent covers and stickers to manufacture this box. We also found some braces removed from an old BT van on eBay which we purchased. There is a good post on the SBMCC (self build motorcaravan club) forums summarises the EN1949 standard which motorhome manufactures follow. 
</value>
<url description="Summary of EN1949 on SBMCC forums" title="Summary of EN1949 on SBMCC forums">http://sbmcc.co.uk/forum/index.php?showtopic=18543</url>
</text>
</section>

&footer;

</page>
