<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!-- Works for Firefox, Safari and Chrome -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="application/xml" href="xsl/html5.xsl" ?>
<!-- Needed for Internet Explorer -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/html5.xsl" ?>

<!DOCTYPE page SYSTEM "./page.dtd">

<page>

&header;

<section name="Why we wanted a conversion" id="main">
<text>
<value>We purchased a townhouse in the costa del sol a few years ago. The only problem was how to transport our boxer dog to and from Cadiz. Both of us did not like the idea of putting Bruno in a plane or leaving him in a car on a boat. We thought about purchasing a motorhome, but we were put off with the expense of them. Louise's dad suggested a camper conversion, they had purchased an LDV 400 Convoy to take their furniture to and from their new house in Malaga. We purchased it off of them and started to plan out Daisy.</value>
</text>

<text>
<value>On looking at how we could convert our LDV we purchased the Haynes book "Build Your Own Motorhome". After reading through it a couple of times we decided to go for the donor caravan approach. Our next task was to find a caravan that would suit the inside of our van. We did not want to pay too much money for a caravan, but we made a list of everything we needed for our journey. It was decided a cassette toilet, shower and water heater was a must for such a long journey. We also wanted a 3 way fridge, cooker and oven. We decided a 6 foot 4 long bed would be best as this would allow Barry some comfort.</value>
</text>

<text>
<value>We were very lucky as we found our donor caravan within a week. It had everything we needed and all furniture could be placed in the van without much modification. We purchased an Avondale Leda Quantock 2 berth Caravan. The picture below shows Daisy pulling the donor caravan from Lochgilphead.</value>
<flickr photoid="113085690" group="caravan"/>
</text>

<text>
<value>The rest of this website shows the various planning stages, any problems we encountered and resolved and all important pictures documenting the build.</value>
</text>

<text>
<value>We applied to have the V5 body type updated from 'Panel Van' to 'Motor Caravan' in May 2009, we were requested to present the van for inspection at the VOSA site in Bishopbriggs. We passed the inspection and the V5 was sent to us a few weeks later with an updated body type. </value>
<flickr photoid="3613875819" group="vosa"/>
<flickr photoid="3613876889" group="vosa"/>
</text>

<text>
<value>The photographs below show the van in one of its incarnations of completeness - after all a camper conversion is never complete. Some of these photographs were used for valuation purposes by our self build motorhome insurer. </value>
<flickr photoid="113085690" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="277725407" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="465952912" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="465979178" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="875476924" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="2414637524" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="2414639068" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="3846100731" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="2414640016" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="2413815655" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="5850403190" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="5850410124" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="5849872137" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="5031382834" group="exterior"/>
<flickr photoid="7639029608" group="exterior"/>
</text>

<text>
<value>Now photographs of inside the van!</value>
<flickr photoid="5849861171" group="inside"/>
<flickr photoid="5849863941" group="inside"/>
<flickr photoid="5849866563" group="inside"/>
<flickr photoid="5850422952" group="inside"/>
<flickr photoid="7174462011" group="inside"/>
<flickr photoid="7359691578" group="inside"/>
</text>

</section>

&footer;

</page>
